Tahmina Khatoon

11/A North Jatrabari, Dhaka – 1204.

E: <u>tahmina8765@yahoo.com</u>
M: +88 017 1653 4860

W: http://bd.linkedin.com/in/tahmina8765



Objective

Sr. Software engineer or Team Lead or Project Management Position to acquire a challenging career with a solid company utilizing the opportunity to offer proven and developing skills within the company.

Professional Profile

Results-oriented, resourceful and problem-solving software engineer professional specialising in large scale software design and development for a wide variety of companies. High level of involvement in the advancement of the industry and adherence to best practice.

Core Skills and Abilities

Experience implementing and supporting large scale software programs

Six years' experience implementing and providing support for new software solutions, and development and assessment of existing infrastructure. Strong focus on design and user capabilities.

Demonstrated experience in project management in a software/IT environment

Extensive experience in project management in software and IT environments across varied clients in the last 6 years. Have managed client networks, government supply chain systems, musical portal software, and ecommerce solutions.

Excellent documentation and communication skills

Successfully documented processes, workflows, procedures and research to the finest detail. Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills with the ability to negotiate effectively with both internal and external stakeholders at all levels.

Excellent UX and web design skills

In last 6+ years' experience, successfully designed 70+ small, medium and large scale website, participates in online contest and have have record to achieve the contest.

Employment History

July 2012 - Present

Software Engineer

Genweb2 Ltd.

Responsibilities:

- Plan, coordinate and conduct multiple complex software engineering activities
- Create and participate in software planning and estimating, status monitoring and reporting
- Devise new approaches, apply existing criteria in new ways and draw conclusions from comparative situations
- Software design, prototyping and investigating
- Software coding and unit testing
- Systems integration and testing
- Software documentation
- Troubleshoot for program errors in existing systems
- Make recommendations on the assessment of tools and software products
- Manage and support other software engineering staff

June 2011 - June 2012

Genesis Systems Ltd.

Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- Web application design and development specially with cakePHP framework
- Systems integration and testing
- Software documentation
- Troubleshoot for program errors in existing systems
- Coordinate with C#.Net team in UI design issue
- System analysis and database design

Nov 2009 - May 2011

Prothom Alo Jobs

Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- Web page (Corporate panel) redesign and development prothom-alojobs.com
- Banner Design
- Customize web page development
- Database management of Prothom alo Jobs
- E-mail Marketing

Sep 2008 - Oct 2009

WEBTECHNOBD

Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- Web page and web related software development
- Server management
- Customers requirement analysis

Education Summary

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (2008)

International Business Administration and Information System University (IBAISU)

Dhanmondi, Dhaka-1209, Bangladesh

Current CGPA: 3.96 (out of 4)

Higher Secondary Certificate (2003)

Motijheel Model High School & College, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Board: Dhaka Board, Bangladesh

Group: Science

GPA Obtained 3.70 (Out of 5.00 without 4th subject)

Grade: A-

Secondary School Certificate (2001)

Motijheel Model High School & College, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Board: Dhaka Board, Bangladesh

Group: Science

GPA Obtained 4.13 (Out of 5.00 without 4th subject)

Grade: A

Academic Achievements

- 1. Achieved "Gold Medal" for academic result of BSCSE degree from IBAIS University
- 2. Achieved "Certificate of Distinction" for six times and "Dean's Award" for one time from IBAIS University
- 3. Participate in Programming Contest in Pioneer "Talent Search" Competition 2006 organized by IBAIS University.

Skills

Programming languages:

PHP

JavaScript

Application Servers:

Apache Nginx

PHP Frameworks:

Zend Symfony Laravel CakePHP

JavaScript Frameworks

AngularJs NodeJs Express Meteor

Databases:

MYSQL MongoDB

Content Management System

WordPress Megento OsCommerce Zen Cart Open Cart PHPBB

Other:

Photoshop
Illustrator
Microsoft Visio
Microsoft Excel
Microsoft PowerPoint
Microsoft Word

Trainings Summary

- 1. **Effective Communication Skills** by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 2. Powerful Business Planning for Success by Prothom Alo Jobs
- Leadership & Team Building Skills for Professional Excellence by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 4. **Customer Service for Excellence** by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 5. Strategic Selling in Competitive Market by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 6. Financial Modeling in Excel by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 7. The Art of Presentation Skills & Public Speaking by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 8. Powerful Business Planning for Success by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 9. Mastering the Art of Selling for Competitive Advantage by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 10. Leadership Excellence for Team Effectiveness & Team Sprit by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 11. Selling Power Excellence by Prothom Alo Jobs
- 12. E-Commerce Applications by osCommerce & Zen Cart by BDJobs

Project Summary

1. Project Name: Indieshuffle

Programming Language: Symfony 2.

URL: www.indieshuffle.com

Description:

- This is an entertainment site having option to hear songs & also organize personal song preferences.
- This application has both web application and mobile application (Android & iOS).
- I worked as a team lead and developer for web application.
- 2. Project Name: Khanahero

Programming Language: Zend Framework 2.

URL: www.khanahero.com

Description:

- Web-based training information management system including jobs information publishing.
- Admin have the full control over website.
- Facebook plug-in integrated.
- 3. Project Name: Hossbrag

Programming Language: Zend Framework 2.

URL: www.hossbrag.com

Description:

- HossBrag is a place for customer-facing members of the Hospitality & Retail Industry to network, promote and collaborate.
- HossBrag gives the opportunity to separate between personal and professional network and keeps personal life personal.
- 4. Project Name: Army POL, Ration & Fodder Supply System

Programming Language: Zend Framework 1.

Description:

• Bangladesh Army has been felt a need of automating their Supply Chain, automated their Ration and fodder supply system.

5. Project Name: Training Bangladesh

Programming Language: CakePHP, AJAX, Jquery, HTML & CSS.

URL: www.trainingbangladesh.com

Description:

- Web-based training information management system including jobs information publishing.
- Admin have the full control over website.
- Facebook plug-in integrated.

6. Project Name: Hygeia Indicative

Programming Language: CakePHP, AJAX, Jquery, HTML & CSS.

Description:

- Web-based laboratory management software solution.
- It is designed to run over both Intranet and Internet and to meet the needs of all diagnostic medical practice offices

7. Project Name: Prothom Alo Jobs

Programming Language: PHP, AJAX, Jquery, HTML & CSS.

URL: www.prothom-alojobs.com

Description:

• Job portal where jobseeker and employers are able to exchange information.

8. Project Name: **Be tourist**

Programming Language: PHP, AJAX, Jquery, HTML & CSS.

URL: www.betourist.lifencolor.com

Description:

- Japanise tour operator if bangladesh
- Admin have the full control over website and user can book a tour package or hotel or they can cancel their previous booking.
- Weather forecast module
- Event Information module

9. Project Name: E-tune24

Programming Language: PHP, AJAX, Jquery, HTML & CSS.

URL: www.etune24.com

Description:

- Online Radio station
- My responsibility is to supervise a web designer and a PHP developer to complete this project.

Web Development

(Listed in Alphabetically Ascending order)

No	Name	URL
1	Aalo Telecom	http://www.aalotelecom.com
2	Acceture Holding & Development Ltd.	http://www.accenturebd.com
3	Afzal Dental Zone	http://www.afzaldzone.com
4	Ahmed Zaker Chartered Accountant	http://www.ahmed-zaker.com
5	Alalam Manob Kallan Foundation	http://www.alalam.com
6	Al-amin Car Center	http://www.alamincars.com
7	Al - Textile Mills	http://www.altex-tote.com
8	Angel Tourism	http://www.angeltourism.com
9	Apparel Designers	http://www.appareldesigners.com
10	Ash Rubi Impex	http://www.ashrubi.com
11	Bangladesh Development Discount	http://www.bddiscount.com
12	Baridhara Auto	http://www.baridharaauto.com
13	Belt Piyal	http://www.beltpiyal.com
14	Be Tourist	http://www.be-tourist.com
15	Chowrangi CNG & Filling Station	http://www.chowrangicng.com
16	City Skin Center	http://www.cityskin.com
17	Fab Collections Ltd.	http://www.fabcollections.com
18	Fuleshwary Trade International	http://www.fuleshwary.com
19	FYLBLOG	http://www.blog.fylblog.com/
20	GED Center Inc.	http://www.gedcenterinc.com
21	Golden Bridge	http://www.goldenbridge.com
22	Green Ever Technology Ltd.	http://www.getechbd.com
23	Gomoti Teach	http://www.gomotiteach.com
24	GTG Demo	http://www.gtg-demo.com
25	Holiday Vision	http://www.holidayvision.net
26	IA International	http://www.iaint.biz
27	ILA Engineering & Air Condition	http://www.ilaacbd.com
28	Islami Somaj	http://www.islamesomaj.org
29	Jahan Properties	http://www.jahanproperties.com
30	Jareer Enterprise	http://www.jareer-bd.com
31	Knit Plus Ltd.	http://www.knitplusltd.com
32	Layer Development	http://www.layerdevelopment.com
33	National Skin Center	http://www.kabirnscbd.com
34	Mid Line International	http://www.midlineintl.com
35	Mighty Thread & Accessories	http://www.mightythread.com
36	Maritime Institute of Science & Technology	http://www.mist.sinbadmaritime.com
37	Modern Telecom System	http://www.moderntelesys.com

38	Mohabbat Print	http://www.mp-mobin.com
39	Mridha Trade International	http://www.mridhatrade.com
40	M. R Auto Engineering	http://www.mrpowerbd.com
41	Ness Tech	http://www.nesstech-bd.com
42	Notre Dame Science club	http://www.ndscbd.org
43	Nuruddin Printing & Packaging Ltd.	http://www.nppbd.com
44	Active Printing & Packaging Ltd.	http://www.nstrims-bd.com
45	Panarab International	http://www.panarabint.com
46	Pan Bright	http://www.panbrightbd.com
47	Priyanka Beauty Parlour	http://www.priyankabeauty.com
48	Prothom-alojobs	http://www.prothom-alojobs.com
49	Nabab Prithimpassa	http://www.prithimpassaestate.com
50	Recent Touch	http://www.recenttouch.com
51	Raj Kamal Corporation Ltd.	http://www.raj-kamal.com
52	Road Runner	http://www.roadrunner.com
53	Samara Limited	http://www.samaralimited.com
54	Sampan Auto Car House	http://www.sampanauto.com
55	Sand Hills Ltd.	http://www.sandhillsltd.com
56	Spotex	http://www.spotex.com
57	Jotis Shasri Shekhor Roy	http://www.shekharroy.com
58	Star	http://www.star-bd.com
59	Training Bangladesh	http://www.trainingbangladesh.com
60	Tithi Bithi Multimedia & Tourism	http://www.tbmtds.com
61	FYL (Forum for Youth Leadership)	http://www.fylblog.com

Personal Information

Present Address : 53/L, Middle Badda, Dhaka-1212.
Permanent Address : 11/A, North Jatrabari, Dhaka-1204.

Personal details:

Name : Tahmina Khatoon
Date of Birth : December 01, 1986

Nationality : Bangladeshi

Religion : Islam Marital Status : Single

References

Available on request.